翻译
渣打毛线 natas Brian_13 幽蓝星晴
shan MO lxbenz 佳东
校对
natas 清野过客 OckRAZOR 17 RN
时间轴
monika-卡 框 17 natas 肉肉 RN
谢谢大家 谢谢各位
Greetings. Thank you
欢迎收看GrandTour
Welcome to The Grand Tour
在这周的节目中
And in this week's program
我开着辆轿车
I drive a saloon car
詹姆斯开着餐车
James drives a catering lorry
理查德来了场械斗
And Richard has a knife fight
让我们来跳舞吧
Let's dance
这些稍后播出 但是首先
That is all to come, but first of all
先说说这集的拍摄地 这里是南非
let me talk you through where we are. It's South Africa
那儿远处 可以看见约翰内斯堡
Over there, in the distance, you can see Johannesburg
这个地方 被誉为人类的摇篮
But this place here is called The Cradle of Humankind
因为考古学家认为
Now it's called that because archaeologists have determined
就在这个地点
it was on this very spot
猿猴进化成了人类
that mankind separated from the ape
好吧 我是说
Well, I mean...
看到了嘛 我们还没开始呢
We haven't even begun
-怎么了 -说句公道话
-What?  -Be reasonable
你是会穿袜子 但是除此之外
You've learnt to put socks on,but other than that, mate...
我只想显得有深度一点 好嘛
Listen, I'm trying to be profound here, OK?
-你继续 -之所以要显得有文化
-Carry on, carry on.  -I'm trying to be profound
因为这是起源之地
Because this is ground zero
这是人类历史开始的地方
This is where all of human history began
所有来到这里的人 都像回到了家
Anyone who comes here, it's like coming home
-杰里米  -又怎么了
-Jeremy.  -What?
我们中某些人从猿进化到人花了多久
How long has it taken some of us to evolve from being apes?
花了有
It's taken
两百万 零一百
two million and a hundred...
你在家看的 可能会奇怪为什么所有人都在鼓掌
You at home may be wondering why everybody here is applauding
这是因为当其余的人类
but it's because while the rest of mankind
正在试图去掌握算术的概念
has managed to grasp the concept of arithmetic
南非的总统 雅各布 祖玛
the President of South Africa, Jacob Zuma...
我该怎么说呢 他并没有掌握
Well, how can I put this? He sort of hasn't
这有个片段 给大家看看
I've got a clip here to show you what I'm on about
我们在此宣布 我们的成员数据
We announce that our membership figures
到达了 769
stood at...769
eight-hundred and...
700...
仔细听好了
Listen properly
76万9千
769 thousand
820...
我是说 说真的
I mean, honestly
有趣的是
The funny thing is...
雅各布 祖玛是个有争议的人物
Jacob Zuma is a bit of a controversial figure here
他最近在家造了个游泳池
He recently installed a swimming pool at his home
然后 因为是用纳税人的钱建的
And then, because he'd used taxpayers' money to do that
他说这其实是为防火而建的储水设施
he said it was actually a water storage facility in case of a fire
所以 换句话说 如果他不小心着火了
So, in other words, if he burst into flames
他可以跳进去自己灭火
he can jump into it and put himself out
在一千……三百 秒里
in ten hundred and... three hundred...seconds.
他还给自己买了辆自称的消防车
He has also bought himself what he claims is a fire engine
这很可以
Nice
他还买了一辆救护车
He's also got himself an ambulance
是的 不能更小心了
Yep. Can't be too careful
在南非驾驶汽车
Motoring in South Africa
最大的问题就是野生动物
Big problem here, of course, is the wildlife
你怎样才能准确地警告驾驶员
because how do you accurately warn motorists
可能有个鹿状的东西在前方
that there may be a deer-y thing ahead
还可能被充满了氦气
and it could be full of helium?
有关部门尝试了下
Well, the authorities have had a go
他们提出了这个标志
They've come up with this as a sign
其实还不坏 只是他们把字打错了
It's not bad, except they've got the word wrong
狒                 狒
什么情况啊
What?
这明明是错的
It's wrong, isn't it?
-这才不是狒狒呢 -这才不是
-It's not baboons  -No, it's not
我们从英国来的 都知道这不是狒狒
We're from England. We know that's not a baboon
这里的狒狒其实是很危险的
Baboons are actually very dangerous here
显然 它们比当地警察更会用枪
Certainly, they've got a better idea of how to handle a gun than the local police
他竟然把这个当折凳用
He's actually using that as a shooting stick
我们能回到节目中来了吗
Shall we get on with the show?
-好想法 好计划 -是的 开始吧
-Yes, good idea. Good plan.  -Yes, let's
让我们从阿斯顿马丁开始
And we start with Aston Martin
因为这个公司最近肯定开了一次会
The company must have had a meeting recently
大老板一定拍板了
and the bosses must have said
到下一部007电影上映还要好几年
"It's gonna be a few years now until the next Bond film is out
那咱们阿斯顿马丁该干嘛
"so what are we gonna do
才能在真空期抢几个头条呢
at Aston Martin to generate some headlines in the meantime?"
因此他们决定
And what they must have decided is
极尽所能的做好一辆车
to make a car that is as good as a car can be
我们可不是说造赛车
They weren't talking about making a racing car
因为比赛规定了引擎标准
because in racing there are rules about how big the engine can be
准许使用哪种轮胎
and what sort of tyres you can use
而且造的也不是公路车
And they weren't talking about making a road car
不然就要遵守排气污染法规
that would have to meet emissions regulations
在悬挂上用舒适的橡胶部件
have comfy rubber bits in the suspension
所有这一切只会减慢速度
And all that stuff would slow it down
是的 他们想造辆不受规则所限的车
Exactly. They wanted to make a car that adhered to no rules and no regulations
他们确实做到了
So they have
这就是成果
This is what they came up with
它价值180万英镑
It costs £1.8 million
它叫 火神
And it's called the Vulcan
惊为天物 不是吗
Spectacular, isn't it?
但不是很实用
But not very practical
哦天呐
Oh, God. Ow!
完蛋 我彻底卡住了
Now I'm totally stuck
哦 可以了
Oh, yeah
你们会把这段切掉的对吧
You will be able to edit this out, won't you?
我才不想别人说我胖
I don't want people thinking I'm fat
好了 我要挂上档
Right. I'm gonna pop it into gear now
动静可能有点大
You may hear this a little bit
踩离合器
Er...foot on clutch
接着就是给7升V12发动机点火了
And now it's time to fire up the seven-litre V12
这很正常
It's quite normal
出发以后 事情并没有转变
When I got going, things didn't get much better
即使是低速 这里还是很吵
Even at slow speeds, it is quite loud in here
所以我要戴着傻兮兮的麦克风
which is why I'm wearing this silly face microphone
你们才能听到我
so you can hear what I'm on about
这台车噪音最大的地方 居然不是引擎
The noisiest part of this car, however, is not the engine
这是刹车声
That's the brakes
这种噪音相当尖
They are quite... They are quite squeaky
听上去像踩在小猪上
It actually sounds like I'm stamping on a piglet
当你深踩油门 情况更糟了
And things get worse when you put your foot down
我不会说这像被一头熊攻击
I'm not going to say that it's like being attacked by a bear
确实不像
because it isn't
但这仿佛 和熊共处一室
But it is like being in a room with a bear
而它正准备攻击你
that's thinking of attacking you
当我把发动机旋钮转到这
At the moment I've turned the engine down on this knob here
转到它最低功率设置
to its minimum setting
它只产生500马力
It's only producing 500 horsepower
所以并不是速度吓人
So it's not really the speed that's scary
哦老天
Oh, God!
是这噪音 这粗糙度和这震动
It's the noise and the harshness and the vibrations
这车的配置很低
It's not a very well-equipped car either
比方说 车窗就没法降下来
The windows don't wind down, for instance
车里也没什么可玩的
There are no toys at all
方向盘也只有半个
And you only get half a steering wheel
可是 你花的180万英镑
However, there is one amazing thing
还是有个神奇的功能
you get for your £1.8 million.
它包含所有在你选择的赛道上
An all-expenses-paid trip to a racetrack of your choice
由阿斯顿马丁的试车手
where an Aston Martin test driver
教你怎么开这车的费用
will teach you how to drive your car
不是用500匹的低功率调教
not with the engine wound down to 500 horsepower
而是调高
but with it turned up...
到了极限
...to the max.
我的天 哈哈哈
Holy cow!
发动机现在输出820匹马力
The engine is now producing 820 horsepower
这速度
And the speed
简直无法想象
just beggars belief
熊进入攻击模式
The bear is in attack mode
数据显示 0到100
The figures say it'll do 0-60
只需2.9秒
in 2.9 seconds
带着这大尾翼最高速度都有335公里
And has a top speed of 208 with that wing on the back
实际感觉要快太多了
But it feels a hell of a lot faster than that
天啊
Oh, God!
你花钱买来的
The other thing you get for your money
还有一大帮机械师
is a squadron of mechanics
但可惜
But sadly..
买不来手刹
not a handbrake
好吧 你听我解释
Right, what I've done now is I've taken... yes...
我把方向盘拆了
I've taken the steering wheel off
于是没法把它挂上档防溜车了
so I can't put it in gear to stop it rolling away
老天
Oh, God
当我最终停下车
When I'd finally got it to stop
把车子举升起来
the jacks were deployed
机械师就开工了
and the mechanics set to work
这就是火神
That's the thing about the Vulcan
尾翼角度 防倾杆 悬挂 刹车
Wing angle, roll bar, suspension, brakes
这些都能根据个人喜好来调整
Everything can be adjusted to suit your personal taste
在装作知道他们在做什么后10分钟
After ten minutes of pretending I knew what they were doing
我回到了赛道
I was back on the track
车子感觉
And the car felt...
还是和之前一样疯狂
just as bonkers as it had done before
但是 我不一样了
However, I've changed
这车我开了
I've been driving this thing now
记不清了 三四个小时
I don't know, three or four hours
我开始理解它了
and I'm starting to... understand it
我开始习惯它了
I'm starting to get used to it
我开始信任它了
I'm starting to trust it
我开始理解
Now I'm starting to understand...
为什么火神能在
why the Vulcan can go round the
意大利南部Nardo赛道
Nardo handling circuit in southern Italy
比迈凯伦P1还快9秒
nine seconds faster than the McLaren P1
9秒啊
Nine seconds
按赛车的标准
in car time
那就是一年啊
that's a year!
你在低速弯里
You get phenomenal mechanical grip
有用不尽的抓地力
in the low-speed corners
在不直道上
and then, on the Isn't Straight
多亏这出色的空动设计
thanks to its aerodynamics
又有1.5吨的下压力
you've got a ton-and-a-half of downforce
然后 还有发动机的动力
Then you have the power from the engine
感觉
which feels, well
很老派
old-fashioned
很彻底
Proper
我很惊讶它居然没有化油器
I'm surprised it doesn't have carburettors
我真的好爱它
I love this thing very much
而我最爱的是
And what I love most of all
这不是一项实验计划
is that it's not a test bed
它不是今后汽车发展的范例
It's not an example of what cars will be like in the future
而是为了颂扬昔日汽车的余晖
It's a celebration of what they were like in the past
它
What it is...
就是老式摇滚乐
is old time rock'n'roll
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you, thank you
非常感谢
Thank you very much
-所以 -什么
-So... -What?
我猜你很喜欢这车
I get the impression you quite liked the car
超乎想象
Oh, it's unbelievable
我最喜欢的是
What I loved most of all is they've made it out of bits
它是由工厂里既有的零件拼凑出来的
that they already had lying around in the factory
就像你从南非回到家
It's like you going home after your tripto South Africa
打开冰箱
opening the fridge
用里面剩下的东西
and using what's there
做了个无比美味的牧羊人馅饼
to make a delicious shepherd's pie
就用串味的牛奶和一片老芝士
What, some stale milk and an old piece of cheese?
-它要价多少 180万镑 -没错
-And it costs £1.8 million? -Yes
换算成兰特是多少
How much is that, Jeremy, in rand?
兰特 南非货币
十亿三千一百万
Ten hundred and 30 million and a million
它百公里加速多少 2.9秒
6But for that it does 0-60 in 2.9 seconds?
几乎和大牛 卡特汉姆R600
So it's nearly as fast as an Aventador or a Caterham R600
艾瑞欧原子V8一样
or an Ariel Atom V8
但要贵太多了啊
but much more expensive!
还不能上路
And not road legal
谢谢你打压我的激情
Yes. Thank you very much for relieving yourself all over my enthusiasm
不客气
You're welcome
这是辆非常棒的车
It is a brilliant, brilliant car
现在只剩一个问题
And only one question now remains
它在我们赛道上能跑多快
How fast will it go round our track
开它的男人觉得英伦范
in the hands of a man who thinks that everything British
基本上就是我党
is basically communist?
他来了
Here he is
有点困惑
Looking a bit confused
好 我们看看这堆螺栓有什么能耐
All right, folks, let's see what this bag of bolts will do
他出发了
And he's off
立刻就上了不直道
and immediately on to the Isn't Straight
进入第一弯
First corner coming up
全油门过弯 胆子很大
And he's flat through there. That is ballsy
降档进入不直道的
Changing down, though, for the second corner
第二个弯
on the Isn't Straight
现在动力全开
but now he can use full power
才800匹
800 brake horsepower?
你开玩笑
Are you kiddin' me?
留你名弯前大力刹车
Now, hard on the brakes for Your Name Here
他肯定会被这车感动
He has got to be impressed with this
大概五万美金
For about $50,000
就能把我的老卡车改纳斯卡风
I could get one of my old trucks NASCAR style
也有800匹了啊
It's got 800 brake horsepower
能去猎鹿
Go deer hunting
后面还能放几头鹿
you got room for a couple deer in the back
这车你怎么放鹿
I don't think you can put no deer in this thing
这里有够多鹿给你撞了
Plenty of deer to run over, though
回到不直道
back on the Isn't Straight
007开这个
James Bond drives one of these
卧槽 范迪塞尔会怼得他菊开肉绽啊
Shit. Vin Diesel would whip his ass
他肯定会 降到1档
Yes, I'm sure he would, but down into first
我不懂这货啊
I don't know about this thing
我说这货像个红头发养子
It's like a red-headed stepchild I'm talkin'
还丑出翔
Be damn ugly
不太确定他过外婆家弯时有没有很专心
Not sure he's fully concentrating past Old Lady's House
地板油通过颠簸路段来到变电箱弯
But he is flat out towards Substation. It is bumpy here.
弯心是新柏油 尾巴会不安份吗
And there's new Tarmac on the apex. Will it kick the tail out?
果然 但问题不大
Yes, it does indeed. He's OK.
到绵羊坡 今天没羊
Into Field of Sheep. No sheep today.
冲过终点
And he's across the line.
赛道真棒啊
Hell of a track, though.
-真不错 -车真大
-It is a hell of a track. -Big car.
不管怎样 我们来看看圈速榜
Anyway, we must now bring up the lap board
看看老美开火神的结果如何
and find out how fast the American got round in the Vulcan.
让我们瞧瞧
Let's have a look.
很快啊
Ooh, it's quick.
你瞧 老派摇滚乐
There you go, see? Old time rock'n'roll.
老派摇滚乐击败了说唱 电子
Old time rock'n'roll has beaten rap and techno.
还有R&B
And R and B.
荣登榜首
And is now at the top.
非常棒 好样的
Very good.
干得漂亮 谢谢你
Well done, and thank you.
现在我们得继续了
Now we must move on.
因为我们现在该去唠嗑街散散步了
好 接着说阿斯顿马丁
Right, sticking with Aston Martin
他们和红牛车队一起
they've teamed up with Red Bull Racing
合作打造了这个
to create this.
它叫做001
It's called the 001.
它搭载一台V12 没有涡轮
It has a V12, no turbos
没有那种混动魔法
none of that sort of hybrid witchcraft.
但它能输出900马力
Yet it produces 900 horsepower
而这车只重900千克
in a car that only weighs 900 kilos.
惊人啊
Staggering.
岂止惊人啊 那简直就是神级数据
Well, more than staggering, that is a magic figure,
因为那意味着它的功重比是1:1
cos that means it has one horsepower per kilogram.
而没有车能接近这个数据
And no other car gets close to that.
还差得远 火神几乎只有它的一半
Not remotely. The Vulcan's barely half that.
这很惊人
It's staggering.
这车唯一的问题
The only problem
你只用看着它就知道了
I have with this... and you just have to look at it.
我们还有另一个角度的照片
Another angle we've got here.
看那儿
Look at that.
你就知道这车的重点会是空气动力
You know that car is gonna be all about aerodynamics
特别是下压力
and particularly downforce.
而我讨厌下压力
And I hate downforce.
你啥意思啊 你讨厌下压力?
What do you mean, you hate downforce?
因为他们告诉你说
Because they tell you
你能以160公里时速通过90度的弯
you can go round a 90-degree bend at 100mph
因为空气对车身的下压力
because of the weight of the air pressing down on the body.
像是有一头隐形的大象在上面
It's like having an invisible elephant.
那这头大象摔下来了咋办
What if the elephant falls off?
又不是真有一头大象
It's not a real elephant!
-不可能摔下来 -你又看不见
-It can't fall off!
但你怎么能相信你看不见的东西
But how can you trust something you don't see?
等下 我同意他
Wait. No, I'm with him
万一你突然开进真空里了怎么办
because what if you drove through a sudden vacuum?
但那也不可能发生啊 不是么
Well, that's not gonna happen either, is it?
哈蒙德 听着
Hammond, listen. There has to be a speed
这种依靠主动下压力的车 必然在某个速度
in a car with active downforce, like that one,
当你过弯时 速度快到轮胎无法承受
where you go round a corner too fast for the tyres,
快到抓地力无法支持
too fast for the mechanical grip,
但又没快到下压力能起作用
but not fast enough for the downforce to be working.
所以你就得对警察说
So you'd have to say to the police,
"我是因为开得不够快才撞车的"
"I crashed because I wasn't going fast enough."
-说真的 -是有可能
It's true. -Potentially.
其实还有一点
There's another point, actually,
因为操控要视天气情况而定 是吧
the handling is gonna depend on the weather.
如果天气很炎热
If it's a really hot day
那空气就会更稀薄
the air will be thinner.
不对 是更稠密
No, thicker.
不 热天空气更稀薄
No, it's thinner on a hot day.
看 我已经搞混了
See, I'd be messed up already cos
我就会弄错
I'd have the wrong...
这就是重点啊 天气很炎热
That's the point. You got a really hot day,
你就不想开一辆
and you don't really want to be driving a car
能不能过弯
where whether or not you get round a corner
取决于有没有太阳的车
depends on whether or not the sun's out.
所以你想让天气预报里加上过弯速度
So you now want weather forecasts to include cornering speeds?
不只是天气啊 还有海拔
It's not just weather. Altitude.
在荷兰 零海拔 能开着那车以160的时速过弯
You could drive that car round a corner at 100mph in Holland, sea level,
但这儿呢 海拔1829米
but, what are we here, 6,000 feet up?
这儿海拔1829米
6,000 feet up here.
你能以5公里时速过弯就不错了
You'd barely be able to get round at three mph.
你会撞树上 或者一头真的大象上
You'd crash it into a tree, or a visible elephant.
它们确实是真的
They are real.
没错啊 我就是 说实话
Exactly. I just... Honestly
下压力
downforce...
我不喜欢相信看不见的东西
I don't like having to trust something you can't see.
就像朝鲜一样
It's like North Korea.
或者像避孕药
Or the contraceptive pill.
说得有点儿多
That was an overshare.
其实还有一辆我想让你们注意的超跑
There's actually another hyper car I want to draw your attention to.
威龙的替任者
Replacement for the Veyron.
那是布加迪 Chiron
That is the Bugatti Chiron.
它搭载了一台8升W16四涡轮发动机
It's got a quad turbo 8-litre W16 engine,
每分钟能吸入60000升空气
which every minute inhales 13,000 gallons of air.
-想象下 -难以置信
-Just imagine -It's unbelievable.
1500马力
1,500 horsepower.
而最高时速被限制在420公里
And the top speed is limited to 261 mph.
他们说能达到463公里
They say it would do 288
但在公路上是不负责任的
but that would be irresponsible on the road.
为了音质更好 它音响里还有钻石
It's got diamonds in the speakers for better sound quality.
它当然有咯
Of course it has, yeah.
这点你会喜欢的
Oh, you'll like this.
在极速时 每个轮胎上的力达3800G
At top speed, the force on each tyre is 3800G.
9G就能让人丧生
A man dies at 9G.
如果你极速驾驶Chrion的话
If you drive the Chiron flat out
它将在9分钟内耗尽油箱里的油
it'll drain its tank in nine minutes.
9分钟
Nine minutes?
等一下 420公里时速开9分钟
Hang on a minute. 261mph at nine minutes.
那就是说你每开63公里就得加油
That means you'd have to fill up with fuel every 39 miles.
实际上还不到63公里
Well, less
因为不能开到干 你得尽早寻找加油站
- you can't drive until you run out, you'd have to look for a petrol station.
是的 詹姆斯 这车太不实用了 是吧
Yes, James, it really isn't a practical car, is it?
但我要给你们说下最厉害的数据
Gonna give you the most amazing stat, though.
和这车本身没关系
It's about the people who are buying this car.
而是和要买这车的人有关系
他们目前为止接到了200个订单
They've got 200 orders so far.
而平均下来 每个预订了一辆的人
And the average person who's ordered one
都已经拥有了64辆车
already has 64 cars
3架直升机
three helicopters
3架飞机和1辆游艇
three jets and one yacht
是说祖玛么
Zuma.
雅各布·祖玛 南非总统
我猜他已经买了一辆了
I reckon he's got one already.
没说 他可没说过
Didn't say that. He didn't say that.
我们能继续么
Shall we move it on?
在南非 每天会发生35起劫车案件
In South Africa, there are 35 carjackings every day.
-每天? -每天
Every day? -Every day.
我不得不说
I've got to say
干得漂亮 这数目很惊人啊
well done, that's an amazing figure.
难以置信 你们哪有时间来这儿啊
I can't believe it. How have you got time to come here?
你们有活儿要干吧
Cos you've got stuff to do.
他们都是开别人的车来的
They've all come here in someone else's car.
哦 所以你们是已经抢完了
So you've already done it?
我懂了
I Understing
但他们没意识到 回去只能靠走的了
But what they don't realise is they're all walking home.
好吧
Anyway
总之
emmm
我做了点儿调查
I've done a bit of research.
被劫的最多的车
The most commonly jacked cars
被劫的车
carjacked cars
是大众Polo 丰田海狮 丰田海拉克斯
are the VW Polo, the Toyota Hiace and the Toyota Hilux.
但它们是在南非卖得最好的车
But they're the best-selling cars in South Africa.
没错 大众Polo是南非的销量冠军
Exactly. The VW Polo is the best-selling car in South Africa.
那你们为啥要买一辆
So why would you buy a car
会增加你被爆头和被偷的几率的车
which increases your chance of being shot in the head and your car being stolen?
你们为啥不买一辆没人想偷的车
Why not buy a car that nobody would want to steal?
对啊 如果我住这 我就不会买那些
No, cos if I lived here
我会买辆米色的沃尔沃旅行车
I'd get something like a beige Volvo Estate.
那明明就是你想要的车
That's just a car you want!
你在拿这事当借口 买你的梦想之车
You're using it as an excuse to get your dream car.
听着 哈蒙德
Look, Hammond
我以前给你解释过
I've explained it to you before.
买一辆沃尔沃旅行车 有点儿像是去看牙医
Having a Volvo Estate is a bit like needing to go to the dentist.
这是注定的事 早晚得解决
It's gonna happen. Get it over with.
买就是了
Just do it.
我不想把它解决了
I don't want to get it over with.
因为那像是去对牙医说
That's like going to the dentist and saying,
"把我的牙全拔了"
"Take all my teeth out"
"反正它们都会掉光"
"cos they're gonna fall out."
或者是去理发店说
At the barber's
"拔光 反正它们都会掉完的"
"Just pull it all out, it'll fall out anyway."
或者去看医生
The doctor
"你能让我尿失禁吗 反正都得尿的"
"Stop me being able to retain my urine. It's gonna happen, too."
我要把自己活埋了
I'm gonna bury myself
然后一次性解决所有问题
and get it all over with once and for all
说真的 他说得有道理
He has got a point, seriously.
在必须买沃尔沃之前 先好好享受吧
Let's enjoy it before we have to have the Volvo.
但你们为啥要买会被抢劫的车啊
But why do you all buy cars that you're going to get carjacked in?
有人开大众Polo么
Has anyone got a Volkswagen Polo here?
你有
You have?
那车你自己买的吗
Did you buy that for yourself?
你爸给你买的
My dad bought it for me
哇喔 这个礼物好啊
Oh, nice gift!
这是有多疯啊
What sort of madness is this?
那有人开丰田海拉克斯吗
Has anyone got a Toyota Hilux?
有哈 这是疯了
Yeah. This is insanity.
是你的么
Is it yours?
今早上出门你开的啥
What did you start out with this morning?
难以置信啊
It's unbelievable.
总之 继续往下说
Anyway, listen, we gotta move it on.
因为 在南非这儿
Because, here in South Africa,
人们有个防止盗车的办法很有意思
people have an interesting approach to preventing car theft.
这儿有张图 是一个人的办法
Got a picture here of one man's solution.
那是条巨蟒
That's a python.
没错 这样肯定有用
Now there's no question it's gonna work
仪表盘上有那玩意儿的车
I would not steal a car
我是不会去偷的
that had that on the dashboard
然而 一条巨蟒不像防盗报警器
However, a python's not like a burglar alarm
你不能把它关了
You can't turn it off
那当你上车时
When you come back to your car
该怎么给那条蛇解释
how do you say to the snake
"这是我的车 别勒死我"
"It's my car, don't strangle me."
你没办法
You can't
我很确定你是没法训练巨蟒的 是吧
I'm pretty sure you can't train a python, can you?
当然不能 所以你从没看到过牧羊蛇
You can't. That's why you never see sheep snakes
或者帮助盲人的导盲蛇
or guide snakes for the blind
这从未有过
It'll never happen
但我得说 我得说
I have to say
在英国我们有个更蠢的办法
in England, we've got an even more stupid solution
有人想出了一个叫做 单车地雷 的点子
This chap's come up with an idea called "Bike Mine"
这儿有个他解释这办法的视频
I've got a video of him here explaining how it works
它能快速地装上 来保护几乎任何个人财产
It can be attached quickly to protect almost any personal possession
不管是放在室外 或是车库里 棚子里的
you store outside or in a garage or shed.
它坚固的钢结构被一层橡胶包裹着
Its robust steel construction is covered in a rubber skin
以保护你的财产
to protect your property.
单车地雷 很安全
Bike Mine is safe
因为它上面的雷管是独立的
because the detonators are self-contained...
并且是可以合法拥有和使用的
as well as legal to own and use.
单车地雷 很可靠
Bike Mine is reliable
因为没有电池也就不会耗电
because there are no batteries to run down
而且只有一个活动部分
and only one moving part
这绝对管用
It's not gonna work.
我不能理解的是
What I can't understand is
他说的是它也能用来保护
he said it can also protect
你所拥有的任何其它个人财产
any other personal property you may have
啥 比如明朝的花瓶
What, like a Ming vase?
你担心你的孩子被绑架吗
"Are you worried about your child being kidnapped?
只需要把炸弹挂在他们脖子上
Simply hang this bomb round their neck
下面来到约旦 奇怪吧
So, moving on, to Jordan, weirdly
当地政府刚建了座实训基地
where the government has just built a mock town
世界各地的特种部队
so that special forces from all over the world
都可以来这里
can turn up and have a competition
一决高低
to see which one is best
没错 而今年
Yes, and this year
掌管大权的胖子威尔曼
Mr Wilman who is the Fat Man who controls our lives
威尔曼 节目总编剧
决定让我们也去参加一下
decided that us three should go and take part
显然其中会有大量枪战
Obviously there'd be a lot of shooting
跑动以及翻爬
running about and doing somersaults
我们没一样擅长的
None of which we'd be any good at
但英国特种航空队 世界第一支特种部队
No, but, the SAS, the world's first special forces unit
创立要义就在于迅速
was created to be fast
迅速切入战场迅速撤离
to get into the battle quickly and then get out again
高速驾驶也是重头戏之一
So there would also be a lot of high-speed driving
额 对我明白
Yes, I know
他确实是个问题 我们要想办法
That is a bit of a problem. We'll gloss over that
于是我们前往战场 以下是详细情况
Anyway, we were sent out there and this is what happened
就是这里
This is it.
坐落于安曼深处的特训基地
The special forces training base deep inside Amman.
坐落于安曼深处 与坐落于男性深处 同音
是说城市 没别的意思
The city, obviously, not... not...
总之 一支特种小队将会
Anyway a squad of special forces soldiers
展示我们接下来要做的事
arriving now to demonstrate what we'd have to do later
首先从黑鹰直升机上索降
They exfoliated from a Black Hawk helicopter on ropes
然后攻入一栋恐怖分子控制的建筑
and then fought their way through a terrorist-infested building
随后偷一部车
Their next task was to steal a car
前往被劫持的航班
which they used to reach a hijacked airliner
攻进客舱 杀光坏蛋
Here they stormed the cabin, killed the bad guys...
营救目标人物
and rescued a VIP
接下来 高速追车 行进中枪战
There was then a high-speed car chase and a running gun battle
将被救人质护送至
as they escorted the rescued hostage
就近的大使馆安全区域
to the safety of a nearby embassy
真让人印象深刻啊
That was quite impressive
他们用的不像是实弹
Well, it's not like they were using real bullets
不 是实弹 -明明不是 -是的
-Yes, they were -They were not -They were!
你是说 在这种
Are you saying that on this
老实说就是 训练场中
let's be honest, training ground
人们可以用装了实弹的枪打来打去
people are allowed to run around with real bullets in these guns?
-是啊 -胡说
-Yes -Rubbish.
看吧 实弹
And there you are. Real bullets
我简直是朝自己射了
And I managed to shoot myself
是吗 你怎么弄的
-Oh, yeah -How did you do that?
因为这突击步枪 弹壳从这方向出来
Well, because, on an assault rifle, the bullets come out this side
我习惯左手持枪 弹壳直接打我手臂上了
and I'm a left-handed shot, so they just go up my arm, the casings
你打枪真垃圾
You're gonna be rubbish at this
那我就没法用突击步枪了
Well, I'm not going to be able to use an assault rifle
我都没法攻进那架飞机
I'm not gonna be able to storm that airliner
我都没法从直升机上下来
I'm not gonna be able to get out of the helicopter
正担心事情可能不会很顺利
Fearing that things may not go well
我们被通知去做准备
we were told to go and get ready
没想到连这都困难重重
And even that was fraught with difficulty
你为什么穿成白色
Why are you wearing white?
雪地迷彩啊
Snow camouflage
约旦就从没下过雪
It has never, ever snowed in Jordan
我之前不知道约旦在哪
I didn't know where Jordan was
你会很显眼
You're gonna be quite visible
这时 我们收到老大发来的任务说明
At this point, we received details of our mission from our boss
威尔曼先生
Mr Wilman
只要其中一人死亡
Each time one of you is killed
你们全部都要重新开始
you all have to begin again
像是汤姆克鲁斯电影啊
So it's like that Tom Cruise movie
花心情圣吗
What, Cocktail?
不是花心情圣 也不是雨人
No, not Cocktail. Or Rain Man
这永远也完不成啊
This is gonna take forever
很快我们便乘直升机
Nevertheless, we were soon in the helicopter
前往这次重要营救任务的起点
on our way to the start of this important rescue mission
我们先缕清楚
Let's just get this straight
我们到达建筑上空时
When we get over the building
从舱门跳出去
we leap out of the door
抓住绳索然后滑下去吗
and grab the rope and slide down it?
差不多是这样 是这么玩的
Pretty much, yeah, that's it. That's how it goes
你可以带头
You could be leader
冲出去 做个示范 我们会跟着的
Get out there, show us how it's done, we will follow
我不想去
I don't want to
我这辈子从来没爬过绳子
I've never climbed a rope or gone down one in my life
多好的机会 该抓住啊
Well, what a time. Get on with it
你为什么不先去
Why don't you go first?
我做不到 我恐高
I can't do that. I'm scared of heights
以身作则吧
Lead by example
-鼓舞下你的团队 -说得好
-Be an inspiration to your men. -Yeah, exactly
高度有多少
How high will it be?
有10米 差不多吧
30 feet?
从10米高度摔下去会怎样
What happens if you fell 30 feet?
还能完整的回家吗
Would you be going home with a head wand?
你还会坐这架飞机回去
You'd be going home in this helicopter
不过不是坐座位上
but not in that seat
你会被装在角落的桶里
You'd be in a bucket in the corner
来吧 大干一场吧
OK, here it comes. Let's do this!
哇 老天爷 停下
Whoa! Jesus Christ! Stop!
噢 我靠
Oh, shit
我好害怕
I'm very scared
老兄 这态度不行
Mate, that's not the attitude
-冲吧 -我不喜欢这个
-Go on, then! -Don't like it!
-滑下绳子去 -我不想
-Go down the rope! -Don't want to do it.
-手松一点 -我不想这么做
-Loosen your hands a bit. -I don't want to.
你想让我挠你肚子吗
Do you want me to tickle you on your belly?
-不想 -那快去做啊
-No. -Well, go on, then!
-哈蒙德 -怎么了
-Hammond! -Yeah?
我裤子掉了
My trousers have fallen down
查克·诺里斯 著名银幕硬汉
女士们先生们 简直是查克 诺里斯啊
Ladies and gentlemen, Chuck Norris
噢不 天哪
Oh, no, no
终于到了 你们此生
Oh, yes. Have you ever in your whole life seen anything...
有曾见过什么比这
啊
Oh
事情被我搞的显得有点难
但其实超级简单的
but actually it's surprisingly easy
所以这次不如你先上吧
So, why don't you go first?
-我有个更好的主意 -什么
-I've got a better idea. -What?
为什么不直接降落直升机
Why don't we just land the helicopter?
好主意 直升机都能落地的
That is a good idea. Helicopters can land
停住停住 哈蒙德
Stop, stop, stop. Hammond
这样 你打开门
Right, listen, you open the door
我丢个震撼弹进去
and I'll throw this stun grenade in
好主意 倒数三...
Good idea. In three...
-不 等下等下 -怎么了
No, wait, wait!
我不知道怎么用
I don't know how it works.
噢老天爷啊
Oh, for God's sake
准备好了吗 哈蒙德
Right. You ready, Hammond?
上啊
Go!
冲啊
Come on!
你不是说震撼弹吗
I thought you said it was a stun grenade?
烟幕弹 说错了
I meant smoke
我啥都看不见
I can't see a thing!
完全瞎了
Literally nothing
等烟雾消散了 我们开始搜查建筑
When the smoke finally cleared,we started our sweep
安静
Ssh. Quiet
这代表有狗 是有狗吗
Dog. Dog.
不 我是说门 那有扇门
No! It means door. There's a door!
这有扇门
There's a door.
你以为它是足球吗
It's not a bloody football, is it?
踹开它 用脚平着踹
Kick it You put your foot flat.
就这么干
That's how you do it
没人在 空的
Nobody there It's empty.
没人
Nobody there
很快 人来了
Soon, though, they were there
我们困在房间里了
We are trapped in this room
为什么不从窗户出去
Well, why don't we just go out of the window?
可以从窗户出去啊
We could go out of the window.
好像是可以 掩护我们
Yeah, we could do that. Cover us
好 我掩护你们
Yeah, I'll cover you
在杰瑞米的火力掩护下
As Jeremy laid down covering fire...
梅和我从窗户爬了出来
...May and I climbed out of the window
但随后问题来了
But then, there was a problem
我卡住了
I'm stuck
挤出来啊
Well, push!
-怎么了 -恐怖分子进房间了
-What? -The terrorists are in the room
你怎么知道
How do you know?
他们在搞我
They're doing things to me
好难受啊
This is very uncomfortable
可能是你太紧张了
It's probably cos you're so tense
噢 詹姆斯
James!
-干嘛 -杀了我
-What? -Kill me.
-打死我吧 -乐意之极
-Shoot me. -Gladly
麻烦快点
Please hurry up
全自动模式 额
Fully automatic?
快点动手啊
Get on with it!
给他个痛快吧 倒数十
Just give him the lot. In ten...
不要倒数十了
Not ten!
好吧 倒数三
All right, in... three
二 一
two, one.
这都能打偏
How did you miss?
都说自动步枪开火很不准
It's true what they say about machine guns.
果然如此啊
You can't hit a thing with them.
-干嘛 -快杀了我
-What? -Just kill me.
我们在努力 没那么容易的
We're trying! It's not that easy
等下 我没子弹了
Hang on. I'm out
-用铲子拍死我吧 -好吧
Use the shovel. Hit me with that. -Right
有什么遗言吗
Do you want to say anything?
有 最后一句 我恨你们
Yes. Final words. I hate you
你知道 我做梦都想这么干
You know, I've dreamt about exactly this
-快点啊 -接招吧
-Hurry up! -Incoming!
我们困在房间里了
We are trapped in this room
为什么不从窗户出去
Why don't we go out of the window?
我可以从门出去吗
Do you mind if I go through the door?
这样好多了
This is better
我们英勇地消灭了外边所有敌人
Heroically we fought off all the attackers outside the building
但被一个狙击手盯上了
But then we were pinned down by a sniper
-詹姆斯 詹姆斯 -什么事
James. James. -What?
去把那辆雷诺偷来
Go down there and steal that Renault
为什么
Why?
因为这是汽车节目 我们要有汽车元素
Because this is a car show. We need a motoring element.
-有道理 -去吧
Good point. -Go!
你觉得在这颗星球上
Can you think of anybody on God's green Earth
还有比他更不靠谱的吗
less able to do this kind of thing than him?
我承认他会弹大键琴
I mean, he can play the harpsichord
大键琴 类似钢琴的一种乐器
然而现在并没有什么卵用
but that's not a skill we're gonna need today.
而且他还中枪了
And he's been shot
-詹姆斯 -干嘛
-James. -What?
-去把那辆雷诺偷来 -为什么
-Go and steal that Renault over there. -Why?
因为这是汽车节目 我们要有汽车元素
Because this is a car show. We need a motoring element
有道理
Good point
你觉得在这颗星球上 还有比他更不靠谱的吗
Can you think of anybody on God's green Earth
你觉得在这颗星球上 还有比他
Can you think of anybody on God's green Earth...
你觉得在这颗星球上
Can you think of anybody...
你觉得
Can you think...
詹姆斯 你不能总是一遍遍做同样的事情啊
James, you can't just keep doing the same thing over and over again
不 他一定会失手的
Nah, he'll miss eventually
-噢天啊 -你看吧
Oh, for God's sake. -There it is
因为老顽固下士不肯妥协
Because Corporal Stubborn wouldn't budge from his tactic
理查德和我一致决定
Richard and I decided that on our next attempt
下次我们要带点新装备参战
we'd go into battle with some new equipment
去把那辆雷诺偷来
Go and steal that Renault
Go and steal that Renault over there
詹姆斯 去把那辆雷诺偷来
James, go and steal that Renault over there
-我不 -你什么意思
No. -What do you mean, no?
那边有个车库 里面肯定有车
Well, there's a garage over there. It'll have some vehicles in it
对噢
Oh, yeah
这才像是汽车节目嘛
Now we're in a car show
很好 杰里米你去解决那个狙击手
Right, Jeremy, you go sort that sniper
我们来发动这些车
we'll get these started
好主意
Good plan
里面没有钥匙 我来搭线点火
Right, there's no keys. I'll hotwire it
噢 他躲在那里
Oh, there he is
和我的小伙伴问声好
Say hello to my little friend
电影 疤面煞星台词
耶 这一枪如有神助
Yes! What a shot!
呃
下次就没有这么好的准头了
I'll never be able to do that again.
-杰里米 -怎么了
-Jeremy! -What?
詹姆斯把自己电死了
James has electrocuted himself
这蠢货
Oh, what a...
和我的小伙伴问声好
Say hello to my little friend
里面没有钥匙 我来搭线点火
Right, there are no keys. I'll hotwire it
你从来没看过电影吗
Have you not seen every single movie ever made?
没有放枪的地方 要给奥迪扣一分
There's nowhere to put a gun. That is a bad mark for Audi
运动模式 关闭牵引力控制系统
Sport, drive, traction control off
出发
Here we go!
...未完待续
难以置信
Unbelievable
-杰里米 -怎么了
Jeremy. -What?
你的裤子为什么会掉
Why did your trousers fall down?
因为上面挂了太多手榴弹
Because there were so many grenades attached to them
在直升机的倒灌风之下
And in the down-draught of the helicopter...
我可是很勇敢的 真的
I was very brave doing that. I was
-我确定我看到他哭了 -那是勇敢的泪水
-I'm sure I saw him crying. -They were tears of bravery
噢人们都这么说 勇敢的泪水
Oh, that well-known expression. Tears of bravery
言归正传 在南非有那么一股潮流
Anyway, look, there's a bit of a trend in South Africa
就是自己造车
for making your own car
我是说从零打造一辆车 完全自己来
making a car from scratch
举个例子
We've got an example here
有人用一台宝马318i的引擎和一部分零件造出了这个
This man's built this one based around the engineand a few bits from a BMW 318i
实话实说 看着还挺酷的
And I've got to say, I think that's pretty cool
-真的不错 -还有很多这种例子
It's brilliant. -There are lots of these
我更喜欢这台 同样使用了宝马的引擎 不过是V8
I prefer this one, also with a BMW engine, a V8
可车身却是用牛仔布做的
but the bodywork is made of denim
真是好审美啊
A man of exquisite taste
但我认为其中最好的一台 简直太棒了
I think the best of them all is so good
事实上我们把它请进了演播室
we've actually brought it into the studio
大家看这里 真是难以置信的杰作
Look, it's down here. Unbelievable, this
这是一台梅赛德斯奔驰C9的复制品
It's a replica of a Mercedes C9
你知道吗 哈蒙德 就是它夺取了
Now that, Hammond, was the car
1989年勒芒24小时耐力赛的冠军
that won the 24-hour Le Mans race in 1989
实在是太棒了 我特地请来了它的制造者
And it's so amazing, I've brought out the man who built it
女士们先生们 有请约翰 阿克曼
Ladies and gentlemen, give him a warm hand. Johan Ackermann
感谢你的到来
Thank you very much for coming
我能问一下
Can I just as--
约翰 我能问一下吗
Can I just ask, Johan
你是怎么打造出这些线条的
how did you get the styling to work?
嗯 杰里米 网上并没有这车的图样
Well, Jeremy, there was no drawings on the internet
所以 我找了份写有比例的说明书
so, erm... I got a book on the dimensions
但我找到最接近的也只是这1:32的模型
but the closest I could get was a 1:32-scale model
等等 你是说先测量了模型
Hang on, so you measured your toy car
把数据乘以32 然后造出这辆全尺寸的?
multiplied it by 32 and built a full-sized one
-对 -真是这么造的啊
-Yep. -That's how you did it?
-可以合法上路吗 -完全合法
-Is it road legal? -Fully road legal
-这不是模型 是真车吧  -没错
-It's a real car, not a model? -Yeah
你造这车花了多久
How long did you spend building this?
从动工到完成 一共16个月
From start to roadworthy was 16 months
好吧 在这期间
Right. Was there, or is there
你夫人有想过离婚吗
a marriage to have survived this?
希望她没有
Well, I hope so
毕竟她还在现场 这应该是个好迹象
My wife is here, so it must be a good sign
你好 耐心的女士
Hello, patient lady
真了不起 干得漂亮
Well, it's a remarkable achievement, and well done.
请各位献上掌声吧 Johan Ackermann
Ladies and gentlemen, Johan Ackermann
太赞了
That's brilliant
接下来是一个全新的环节
We're moving on to a great idea
完全是我和哈蒙德的原创
that Richard Hammond and I have had all by our own
-而且真的很精彩  -确实
-And it is brilliant.  -It is.
请看——"詹姆斯梅 我们就是强你所难"
It's called, Making James May Do Something He Doesn't Want To Do.
我们将以画圈开头
And we kick off with spinning
这是南非的特色 非常简单
It's a South African thing. Fairly simple
先找辆上了年纪的后驱车
You get an elderly rear-wheel-drive car
开到一个停车场
take it to a car park where you do doughnuts in it
伴着节奏感极强的说唱  漂移画圈圈
to a backdrop of strong rap music
这活动集活力 趣味 年轻化 于一体
It's lively, it's interesting, and it's youthful
完全就是他的对立面
It's everything he isn't
就是这了
Well, here we are, then
Jo'burg的最佳转圈场地
at one of Jo'burg's top spinning destinations,
Jo'burg 约翰内斯堡 流行俚语
人们形象地称之为'车轮与浓烟的禁地'
the aptly-named Wheelz 'n' Smoke Arena
这种活动的意义在于
And the object of the exercise
要我说
as far as I can make out
就是为了拉烟
is to create smoke
在场内一圈一圈的转
And drive round and round the arena
直到爆胎
until the tyres go bang
而破轮胎的残骸
And then what's left of the tyres
会丢进那边的火堆
are put on a bonfire over there
这是为了保证轮胎完全无残留
to make sure there's absolutely nothing left
这是史黛西 我猜 她今年才17岁
This is Stacy, and she's only about 17, I think.
坊间传闻以及群众们的欢呼声
And the word round here and the noise in the crowd
都表明史黛西是个中高手
says that Stacy is actually very good at this
但我不确定啊 眼前尽是白烟
But how the bloody hell would I know? It's just a massive cloud of smoke...
偶尔模糊地看到头灯
...with some headlights occasionally appearing in it
为了帮助我理解这项活动的意义
To help me get into the spirit of things
举办者们觉得我应该亲身经历一下
the organisers suggested I should become more involved
天啊
伙计 快看转速表 一直在红区里
Look at the rev case, in the red constantly, mate
我并不喜欢晚上胎烟的味道
I don't like the smell of tyre smoke in the evening
喂 快回来
Oi! Get back in!
回到车里来 你***的
Get back in the car, you [BLEEP] idiot!
救命
Help!
谢谢
Thank you.
-爆了没  -爆了
-Has it broken?  -Yes.
终于
Finally.
之前我车上的轮胎
I got 20,000 miles
足足开了32,000公里呢
out of the last set of rear tyres on my car
鼓起勇气开一轮啊
Just go out there and do it
想想如果在英国这么玩
Fancy trying to do that in England
或者任何地方 比如澳大利亚
Or anywhere. Or Australia
不管怎么说 咳咳
Anyway, mm-mm-mm
詹姆斯 当时你享受过哪怕一秒钟吗
James May, was there any part of that that you enjoyed?
-没有  -很好
Nope.  -Good.
现在到了明星脑碰脑环节
But now it is time for Celebrity Brain Crash
自从上周发生的不幸之后
Now after what happened last week
这周的嘉宾拒绝
our guest this week declined our offer
乘坐气垫船出场
to arrive at the studio on a hovercraft,
她表示宁愿步行
saying she would prefer to walk
-这可以理解  -是的
-It's understandable.  -Yes, it is.
我肯定 尽管如此
I'm sure that despite this
你们还是会热烈欢迎这位嘉宾
you will still give her an enormous welcome
因为 虽然她现在已是好莱坞大咖
Although she's now a major Hollywood star
但她出生在这 南非
She was actually born here in South Africa
女士们先生们 有请查理兹塞隆
Ladies and gentlemen, please welcome Charlize Theron!
一定要问她有关"死在西部的一百万种方式"的问题
We must ask her about A Million Ways To Die In The West.
我超喜欢那电影
I love that film.
但我最喜欢的是她在里面的造型
But what I really love is the way she looks in it.
帽子和飘飘的裙摆 而且她骑着自行车
The hat and the floaty skirt. She's on a bicycle as well.
-不是吧  -我的天
Oh, no. Oh, God.
-别...  -女士们先生们
- Oh, not...  -Ladies and gentlemen
查理兹塞隆被一头狮子攻击了
Charlize Theron has been attacked by a lion
-不要啊  -我们确实无能为力
- Oh, no.  -Literally nothing we can do.
所以说她来不了吗
Does that mean she's not coming on, then?
她被狮子吃啦
She's been eaten by a lion.
好吧 也许观众中
Well, look, are there any other well-known
有著名的南非明星
South Africans in the audience?
这不太可能 詹姆斯
It's not very likely, James
世界上有名的南非人就两个
There's only two globally famous South Africans
一个在狮子肚子里 还有一个在监狱里
One's now in a lion and the other's in prison
南非刀锋战士
那么 回到之前的话题吧
Let's get back to what we were doing
早些时候 我们在一个约旦特种部队训练基地
Earlier on, we were at a Jordanian special forces training base
学习如何成为超级士兵
learning to be super army soldiers.
接下来我们要冲向一架被劫持的客机
And we pick up the action as we rush towards the hijacked airliner
营救VIP 并护送至安全点
to rescue a VIP and take them to safety.
容我解释这个计划
Let me talk you through the plan
詹姆斯和理查德将开着餐车作为突击车
James and Richard will use the catering lorry as an assault vehicle
然后 我们救到VIP之后
And then, after we've rescued the VIP
再驾驶奥迪跑路
we'll use the Audi as a getaway car
我们现在要机智地
Now what we're doing here, very cleverly
从飞机后面绕过去
is we're going round the back of the plane
因为飞机没有后视窗或反光镜
because planes don't have rear windows or door mirrors
所以他们看不见我们在潜行
so they won't see us sneaking up.
多隐秘啊
Stealthy, you see
哈蒙德 我们溜过去
Hammond, we're manoeuvring in
-好的  -按下气刹
-OK.  -Dab the brakes
好了 我们已就位
Right, we are in position
詹姆斯会把我抬到门边
James is gonna lift me on this platform to the door
然后我们突击
then we go in
你准备好了吗
Right, are you ready?
我准备好放下千斤顶了
I'm ready to lower the jacks
简直太隐蔽了
Absolute stealth
我认为那些恐怖分子
I think the terrorists
会注意到的
are going to notice this assault.
我认为恐怖分子们会注意到的
I think the terrorists are going to notice this assault
因此我要转移他们的注意力
Which is why I shall now cause a diversion
我要在飞机前面画圆拉烟
I'm gonna make a smoking doughnut in front of the plane
来让恐怖分子分心
to distract the terrorists
不好 简直太糟糕了
Oh, no, this is a disaster
即使你把电子牵引力系统关了
Even when you turn the traction control off
也无济于事
it isn't fully off
你只好忍受这漫长无趣的转向不足
so you just get miles and miles of dreary understeer
这点给奥迪差评
Bad mark for Audi here
给点力
Come on!
唯一的好处是
The only good thing is
恐怖分子们确实能透过窗户看到
the terrorists will be looking out of the cockpit windows
还会纳闷 为啥奥迪这么转向不足
thinking, "Why is that Audi understeering around like that?"
好的 趴下
Right! Go low!
我来了
Here I come!
莎翁名言 原句为战争的破坏
为转向不足的破坏而道歉
Cry havoc and let slip the dog of understeer!
两位 我找到VIP了
Chaps, I have located the VIP
她就是英国女王
and it is the Queen of England
我不喜欢皇室
I don't like the Royal Family
詹姆斯 现在不是表达你共和言论的时候
James, now is not the time for your republican views
陛下 我们是精英作战小组
Ma'am, we are an elite fighting force
我们外面停着奥迪 马上
We have an Audi outside. We will...
你为什么对哈蒙德开枪
Why did you shoot Hammond?
他太烦人了
He was being annoying
就这么干
That's how you do it!
夫人 我们是精英作战小组
Ma'am, we are an elite fighting force
我们外面停着奥迪 马上
We have an Audi outside. We will...
-你朝詹姆斯开枪了-他先动手的
-Did you shoot May?  -Well, he shot me!
就这么干
That's how you do it!
然而在下一次尝试中
Somehow in our next attempt
哈蒙德跑到了机翼上
Hammond ended up on the wing
哦 你想玩传统的啊
Oh, I see. You wanna do this the old-fashioned way
好啊 就陪你玩玩
OK, let's dance
夫人 我们是精英作战小组
Ma'am, we are an elite fighting force.
外面停着奥迪 会带您去安全地带
We have an Audi waiting outside to get you to safety
-那你是做什么的 -我说了
And what do you do?  -I just said.
我们是精英作战小组
We are an elite fighting force
外面停着奥迪 会带您去安全地带
We have an Audi waiting outside to get you to safety
-您会喜欢的 德系 -就像您一样
You'll like it, it's German.  -Like you are.
吐槽英女王德国血统
谢了 詹姆斯 后面的恐怖分子死光了吗
Thank you, James. Are all the terrorists dead back there?
-后面所有人都死了 -好样的
-Everybody's dead back there.  -Good man
陛下 请跟我来
Your Majesty, if you'd like to follow us
又怎么了
What was that?
他刚朝女王后脑勺开了一枪
He's just shot the Queen in the back of the head
额 接下来怎么办
Well, now what we gonna do?
哦 次奥
上车吧 这个我来保管 谢谢
Go. I'll have that, thank you very much.
终于把女王带上了车
Having finally got the Queen into the car
我们驶向通往大使馆的危险之路
we were now faced with a perilous drive to the embassy
不过 这也意味我能干回老本行了
However, this did at least mean I could get back to my day job
好好聊聊这车 这是S8 plus
I'll talk you through the car. This is the S8 Plus
plus的意思是比标准版多80匹马力
Plus means it has 80 more horsepower than the standard car
也就是说百公里加速仅需3.8秒
That means 0-60 in 3.8 seconds
极速 304km/h
top speed: 190
挺有意思
How very interesting
驯服这猛兽靠的不光是全时四驱
The immense power is harnessed not only by all-wheel drive
还有陶瓷刹车
but also by ceramic brakes
还有电子差速器
And an electronic differential
这可不是聊车的时候啊哥们
There's a time and a place for talking about that stuff, mate!
坐在一个1米96的司机后面
Sitting behind a six-foot-five-inch driver
意味着后排腿部空间好不到哪去
means that rear leg room is rather at a premium.
话虽这么说
Having said that
作为辆高性能四门车
however, for a high-performance saloon
舒适度是相当可以的
the ride quality is really rather good
你俩能不能别评测车了
Will you two stop reviewing the car?
女王大人您有什么看法
Do you have an opinion, the Queen?
现在不是时候啊
Not now!
开稳点 我要射他们
Hold it steady, I'm gonna shoot them
射他的脸啊
Shoot him in the face!
你是远道而来吗
Have you come far?
女王惯用打招呼方式
007黎明生机 非常人贩2和3 飓风营救 冷血悍将
The Living Daylights. Transporter 2 and 3 Taken Ronin
你为啥要列举电影啊
Why are you listing films?
每部电影里都有大奥迪飞驰的身影啊
Because all those films had a big Audi saloon in them going quickly
好莱坞英雄座驾的不二之选
It is the car of choice for the Hollywood hero
闭嘴
Shut up
詹姆斯 那玩意极速多少
What's the top speed of that thing, James?
不到150km/h吧
About 90 miles an hour.
那么 给好莱坞英雄们一个忠告
Well, here is a top tip for Hollywood heroes
要是追你的车跑不快
If you're being chased by a car which is slower than the car you're in
只需要开的比它快就行
simply drive faster than it
凯奇拍勇闯夺命岛的时候就该好好想想
See, that's what Nick Cage ought to have thought about, really, in The Rock
还有热血悍将里那位 开着S8追雪铁龙
And that man in Ronin, with the S8 chasing the Citroen
别再说电影情节了
Stop talking about films!
有个大家伙逼近我们了
There's a bogey waxing our tail
-天啊 -我要打它油箱
-Oh, God!  -Gonna shoot its petrol tank
詹姆斯 打油箱没用的
James, there's no point shooting it
汽油只会在电影里爆炸
Petrol only blows up in films
好吧 凡事皆有例外
Well, that's not strictly accurate
-那天杀的大使馆在哪 -往前走
-Where the bloody hell is the embassy?  -Go down here.
-扯淡 -到了到了
-No, this is rubbish.  -There it is.
终于到了
There it is!
好 你们带女王去安全的地方
Right, you get the Queen to safety
我掩护你们
I'll cover you
-交给我 -好了 快跑 跑啊
-OK, I'm on it.  -Right, good. Go, go, go!
陛下 咱们得快点 非常快
Really quickly, Your Majesty
我们看不见了
We can't see.
杰里米 快过来 过来啊
Come on, Jeremy, come on!
我已经尽力跑了
I'm doing my best!
正中靶心
In the plums!
别停 接着跑
Oh, no! Just keep moving!
又来一次
They've done it again!
詹姆斯 你要错过这了
James, you're missing this!
您不能把皇权现代化
You cannot modernise the royalty
因为它充其量
because royalty is, at the very best
就是个中世纪的概念
a medieval concept
啊 开枪啊
Oh! Shooting!
又来了一枪 他还在跑
That's gonna sting! He's still coming!
别停 继续跑
Keep going!
小心地雷
Mind the mines!
他还在跑
He's still going!
詹姆斯 他死了
James, he's dead.
等等 他动了 又动起来了
No, wait a minute. He's going again! He's moving again!
加油杰里米 你能做到
Jeremy, come on, you can do it!
加油加油 接着爬
Come on, keep going! Come on
-就差一点了 -哈蒙德
-This is it.  -Hammond...
终点就在眼前了
There's the finish line!
我没走错吧
Am I going the right way?
差不多了 滚过来吧 你行的
More or less. Roll over it. You can do it
我们成功了
Yes! We have done it.
你是远道而来吗
Have you come far?
非常不可思议的作战小组
A fighting force. An unbelievable fighting force
我们花9小时48分完成了这个演习
We actually managed to complete that course in nine hours and 48 minutes
只比真正的军人慢了9个半小时
And that's only nine-and-a-half hours slower than the actual soldiers
我能问下 你到底挨了多少枪
Can I just ask, how many times were you shot?
-冲刺时吗 -往大使馆跑的那段
What, on the run in?  -On the way to the embassy
17枪打到身上 2枪打到了蛋蛋边
Er... 17 to the torso, two to the... plum set
你居然还活着
And you lived?
当然 詹姆斯你看 我活下来了
Well, obviously, James, yes, look, I lived.
确实活下来了 伴随着这糟糕的失望之情
He did. And on that terrible disappointment
我想是结束的时候了
it is time to end
是的 感谢收看
Yes, it is. Thank you so much for watching.
下周我们在别处再相见 拜拜
See you somewhere next week. Goodbye!